hello everyone
today we are going to start a new adventure in gregtech 6
as we look around
we notice some surface rocks
which we can collect and use to craft our first axe
which can be crafted without even a crafting table
this axe is cheap
and capable of chopping down multiple logs at once
but it's slow and it has a low durability
but that's also because we made this axe out of marble pebbles
and if we look around a little bit more
we can indeed find some better rocks
after spending enough time collecting rocks
we figure out that red granite is the best one
tools made out of this rock can even harvest obsidian
but the speed isn't that good
and since those tools are still made out of pebbles
the durability is quite low
but that's not much of a big deal
since we can just look around pebbles
to find more of that material
once we locate the solid rock
we just have to break the stone twice with a hammer
to obtain all of the pebbles we could possibly need
to get better tools we will want to process some metals
but first we will be looking for a nice place
where we can start building our industry
since we might need chlorine in the future
setting by the seaside is probably a good idea
and that totally wasn't an excuse
so we could have a nice sea house with view on the sunset
and after all of that work
we can finally rest a little bit
while eating some sweet berries we found on our way
and that's when we found out that eating too many sweets isn't healthy
the next day we decided to start working on a proper garden to fix our diet
but after removing some rocks
we figured out there was a high concentration of copper in our soil
we started digging deeper to investigate
and we eventually found more and more copper-rich rocks
but copper on its own is an awful material for tools
to make it stronger
we have to add some of the tin we also found in our backyard
but to properly alloy together those two metals
we have to heat up the mixture at 1400K
that has to be done inside a crucible
which we can easily craft with some clay
to heat it up
we turn on a burning box underneath the crucible
now we just have to throw the raw ingredients in
and wait for everything to melt
once the mixture turns the right color
we can pour out the molten metal into a pickaxe mold
to celebrate the advent of bronze age
we can make a jumbo sandwich
which we can eat in a single bite
and that's how long it took for our crucible to turn yellow
and before we could even finish that phrase
the crucible melted
indeed, in gregtech 6, everything has a melting point
how quickly we reach that temperature
depends on the thermal mass we are trying to heat up
and how much heat energy we add to the thing
while we can guess the current temperature just by looking at the color of the crucible
a better way is to craft a thermometer
to craft it, we will need some mercury
so we adventured in search of new minerals
during our exploration
we found huge deposits of coal
and huge deposits of iron-rich sand
underground we found all sorts of ores
some of which were rather hard to notice
we also found a weird building
once inside it turned out to be an abandoned base
stocked with many different chemicals
and a huge amount of all sorts of metals
we even found already worked metal parts in some nearby drawers
and as if all of those goodies weren't enough
we even found the holy grail of the bronze age: a lighter
this one has a 100 percent success rate
and we even have some spare propane to refill it
and while we found mercury in this place
we still explore more areas to secure a proper source
we cross multiple dimensions
until we finally found a redstone vein
which also contains cinnabar a mercury rich metal
we process the raw material to increase the yield
finally we heated it up
to extract some mercury for our thermometer
with this, we can finally measure temperature more precisely
easing the metal alloying process
the next step was to connect our thermometer to a redstone sensor
allowing us to automate a metal alloying
to do so
we first configure our new digital thermometer with the correct temperature
then we connect it to the molds
and enable out output on redstone
next we configure a pair of hoppers with the correct input ratio
and to avoid overfilling our crucible
we use a properly configured weight sensor
and this simple system can easily be expanded
to allow for more complex alloys
such as stainless steel
while this has many usages
we are also going to need some normal steel
which is made by pumping air in a crucible
to do so
we will have to input kinetic energy to the crucible
we can do that by vibrating it using a steam engine
running this machine will require some steam
which it can produce by boiling water inside some boilers
which we heat up using the same burning boxes we use to heat up crucible
and now that we manage to obtain steels
we can do many things
starting from a bigger crucible
this one will be able to fit multiple blocks of metal easing the melting process
and the reason why we have minerals in the form of cubic meter size dust
is our new ore processing plant
the first step is to run our rovers in a crusher
which will break the big rocks into smaller chunks
then we run those crushed rocks in a sluice
to separate the stone from the actual minerals
next we run the purified ores through a centrifuge
to filter out more byproducts
finally, we macerate all of the centrifuged ores in a shredder
to get everything in dust form
however those dusts won't have all the same size
to properly sort out all of those dust
we use a system of hoppers and funnels
to first cluster all of the dust into small size
and then into full blocks
while most of those can be melted into pure metal using a crucible
others require some extra refinement
so we built some ore-specific processing lines
like this one for aluminum
to obtain this MV material
we had to use an electrolyzer
and you may be wondering why we aren't using electricity for other setups
well there are two main reasons
the first one is the horrible efficiency of transforming energy
and here I really want to be pedantic on what I mean with energy loss
we start with a 25 percent loss when burning materials
to produce the heat units required to boil water
then a boiler will convert that heat into steam
if we use distilled water
this process will be perfectly efficient
we pipe the steam to a turbine
which will dissipate one third of the energy
while using the hot gas to spin a rotor
these will produce a rotation unit
which we shaft to a dynamo
here after losing almost one more third of our energy to friction
we finally get electricity
then we have the usual cable loss
which here is negligible
and after losing more than half of the starting energy
we figure out that most machines don't use electricity
so we have to deal with losing another half of our electric energy
to convert it back to whatever we actually needed
the second issue is that
right now we can only shut off machines by cutting the power feed
so if we want to have the comfort of electricity versatility for machines that don't require too much power
we will want some machines switch covers
and also some battery boxes
however both of those things will require some circuit
and even the lowest tier of circuit requires plastic and silicone bottles
while the main issue of silicon is a bit of inert gas and processing time
making plastic has a mandatory titanium tetrachloride requirement
since we needed just a few drops
we manually handle all sorts of chemicals
to process the bauxite leftovers into titanium
chemical reactors aren't a thing here
so we had to deal with all sorts of never seen before machines
and after carefully measuring the correct amount of ingredients
we made our first plastic
with that we had every required ingredient
so we proceeded into quickly working everything into our first electric circuit
we use those to craft some machines which covers
and then we proceeded into building our LV workshop
and since the some machines don't have an integrated motor
we still have to use a some bronze machine powered by dedicated electric motor
we have already seen how inefficient that is
but being able to instantly start and stop those engines from the batteries
is a really nice quality of life improvement
also there are some new forms of energy we can derive from electricity
such as magnetic units made from an electromagnet to power polarizers
and laser units, made by a CO2 laser
which will have many usages in the future
but for now we can use that for a laser engraver
so that we can make LuV circuits, the highest tier available
with those we unlocked all sorts of cool things
and our first objective is going to be a nuclear reactor
to fix our energy production
to get started, we are going to fuel it using uranium 238
which is super cheap
and will keep producing heat for 800 hours
in this setup
we are using some IC2 coolant to get the heat out of the reactor
and bring it to some heat exchangers
where, as usual, we boil water to spin a turbine
and this time
to avoid using expensive cables that will also lose power
we made a long shaft to our base
where we have a small dynamo that slowly charges up some huge batteries
allowing the size for a bigger setup we will eventually build
the first thing we will be using our new power source for
is a thermoelectric cooler
to run our new cryogenic distillation tower
to obtain some noble gasses for a nano-scale fabricator
used to make graphene parts
which have incredible stats despite being super cheap
notably, we can now make carbon crucibles
capable of handling even the toughest materials
we are going to heat it up with our new electric heater
which perfectly manages temperature
and what we just made is tungsten carbide
used to make the better extruder capable of doing all sorts of jobs
however all of those new machines quickly drained our battery buffer
it was clear we needed a bigger nuclear reactor
and to speed up the crafting process
we increased our efficiency by directly connecting our heaviest machinery to our old nuclear reactor
and after crafting a lot of dense plates
we finally completed our new reactor plant
this time we are using six reactor cores
filled with a mix of different rods
achieving a production of over 9000 heat units per thick
we use some of that heater to keep the water loop going
and the rest goes into heating two large invar boilers
those will produce a 16,000 liters of steam per tick
which we use to spin a large turbine
with an output of 5,000 rotation units per tick
finally, a large dynamo will convert that into 4000 EU per tick
just below the IV result
the reason why the output isn't consistent
is that we aren't using that energy
and the batteries in our buffer are fully charged
大家好
今天我们要在格雷科技 6 中展开新的冒险
当我们环顾四周时
会发现一些地表岩石
我们可以把它们收集起来，做出第一把斧头
它甚至不需要工作台就能制作
这把斧头很便宜
而且能一次砍倒多根原木
不过它很慢，耐久也很低
因为它是用大理石石子做成的
如果我们再多看一看
就会发现还真有更好的石子
花了时间收集石头之后
我们发现红花岗岩是最好的
用这种石头做的工具甚至能挖黑曜石
不过速度就没那么快了
这些工具毕竟还是石子做的
耐久还是很低
但这也没什么大不了
因为我们只要再去找找石子
就能找到更多这种材料
一旦我们找到整块的原石
只要用锤子把石头敲两次
就能拿到需要的所有石子
要做更好的工具，我们还要加工一些金属
但首先我们要找个合适的居所
在那里开始建设我们的工业基地
毕竟以后我们可能还需要氯气
所以住在海岸附近应该不错
这当然不是借口
只是为了让我们能有一座美观，能看到落日的海景房
忙完这一切之后
我们终于可以稍微休息一下
一边炫点路上找到的甜浆果
这时候我们发现，吃太多甜食并不健康
第二天，我们决定开始建一个像样的菜园，来调整饮食
但在挖开一些石头之后
我们发现土壤里有很高的铜含量
于是我们开始往下挖，进一步调查
结果挖出了越来越多富铜的岩石
不过铜本身并不是很好的工具材料
要让它更硬一些
还得加入一些在后院找到的锡
但要把这两种金属真正合金在一起
得把混合物加热到 1400 K
这一步必须在坩埚里完成
坩埚可以很容易用黏土做出来
要把坩埚加热
我们在它下面点燃燃烧室
现在只要把原料扔进去
等它们全部融化就行
一旦混合物变成正确的颜色
我们就能把熔融金属倒进镐头模具里
为了庆祝青铜时代的到来
我们可以做一个巨型三明治
然后一口吃下去
吃完了，坩埚也变黄了
话还没说完
坩埚就熔化了
没错，在 GT6 里，万物都有熔点
要多快达到熔点
取决于我们要加热物品的热容
以及我们对它输入了多少热量
虽然我们也能通过坩埚的颜色来大致判断温度
但更好的办法是做一个温度计
要做温度计，我们需要一些水银
于是我们启程去寻找新的矿物
在探索过程中
我们发现了大量煤矿
还有大量富铁砂
我们在地下还发现了各种各样的矿
其中有些还挺难一眼看见
我们还找到了一座奇怪的建筑
进去之后才发现，那是一个废弃基地
里面堆满了各种化学品
还有大量各种金属
我们还在附近的抽屉里找到了已经加工好的金属零件
如果这些都还不够多的话
我们又找到了青铜时代的圣杯：一个打火机
这东西的点火成功率可是 100%
我们甚至还找到了备用丙烷来给它补充燃料
虽然我们在这里发现了水银
但我们还是继续探索更多区域，以确保有稳定来源
我们穿越了多个维度
直到最终找到一条红石矿脉
其中含有朱砂，一种富汞矿物
我们加工原矿以提高产量
最后我们把它加热
提取一些水银做温度计
有了这个，我们终于能更精确地测量温度了
也让合金制作更容易控制
下一步是把温度计接到红石传感器上
这样我们就能自动化合金
要做到这一点
我们先把新的数字温度计按正确温度配置好
然后把它连接到模具上
并在打开“有红石时自动输出”
接着我们设置一对漏斗，调整到正确的输入比例
要避免坩埚被灌满
我们可以用一个调好配置的重量传感器
这个简单系统很容易扩展
来支持更复杂的合金
比如不锈钢
虽然不锈钢用途很广
我们还是需要一些普通钢材
普通钢是通过向坩埚里泵入空气制成的
要输入空气
我们得给坩埚输入动能
我们可以靠蒸汽机来振动坩埚
运行这台机器需要一些蒸汽
而蒸汽可以通过锅炉烧水来产生
加热锅炉用的是和加热坩埚时相同的燃烧室
我们既然已经成功做出了钢
那就可以做很多事情了
先从更大的坩埚开始
这种坩埚可以容纳下一些金属块，简化熔化过程
而矿石之所以会以立方米大小的粉尘形式出现
是因为我们有了新的矿石处理厂
第一步是把原矿送进研磨机
把大块岩石打成更小的碎块
然后把这些碎石送进洗矿槽
把石头和真正的矿物分开
接着把净化后的矿石送入离心机
分离出更多副产物
最后把所有离心后的矿石送进粉碎机
把它们全部打成粉尘
不过这些粉尘的粒度并不统一
要把这些粉尘正确分拣好
我们用的是漏斗和料斗系统
先把所有粉尘聚成小撮粉
再聚成整块
虽然其中大多数都能在坩埚里熔成纯金属
但有些还需要额外精炼
所以我们又建立了一些矿专用的生产线
比如这条铝生产线
要得到这种 MV 级材料
我们不得不用电解机
你可能想问，为什么其他设备不用电力驱动
原因主要有两个
第一个就是能量转换效率低得离谱
这里我要特别较真地解释一下我说的能量损耗
我们先从燃料燃烧时损失 25% 开始算
把燃料转成烧开水所需的热能
然后锅炉再把热量转成蒸汽
如果用的是蒸馏水
这个过程就是完全高效的
我们把蒸汽送进涡轮机
在那里又会损失三分之一的能量
同时用高温气体去带动转子
这样就会产生转动能
再把它传给发电机
这里又因为摩擦损失了将近三分之一的能量
最后我们才真正发出电来
然后还有常见的电缆损耗
不过在这里几乎可以忽略不计
等我们损失掉超过一半的初始能量后
就会发现大多数机器根本不用电
所以我们还得再把剩下那一半电能转回去
变成我们真正需要的能量形式
第二个问题是
现在我们只能通过切断供电来关闭机器
所以如果我们想让那些耗电不多的机器也能方便地使用电力
就需要一些机器开关覆盖板
再加上一些电池箱
不过这两样东西都需要电路板
但最低级的电路板也要塑料和硅胶瓶
硅的主要问题在于需要惰性气体和处理时间长
而制作塑料则必须用到四氯化钛
因为我们只需要几滴
所以我们直接手搓这些化学品
用来铝土矿废料处理成钛
GT6 并没有化学反应釜这种东西
所以我们只好面对各种前所未见的机器
仔细量好正确配比之后
我们做出了第一批塑料
这下所需材料就全齐了
于是我们很快把所有材料搓成了第一个电路板
我们用第一批电路板来制作机器开关覆盖板
然后开始建造我们的 LV 车间
而且因为有些机器没有内置电机
我们还是得用一些由专用电机驱动的青铜机器
我们已经见过这有多低效
但能用电池瞬间启停这些引擎
确实是个很不错的体验提升
另外，我们还能从电力中得到出一些新的能量形式
比如用电磁铁制成的磁能，用来驱动极化器
以及由二氧化碳激光器制成的激光能
它们未来会有很多用途
现在，我们可以先用它来做激光刻蚀机
这样就能制作 LuV 电路板，目前最高等级的电路板
有了这些，我们就解锁了各种很酷的东西
我们的第一个目标是建造一座核反应堆
来填上我们的能源生产
首先，我们打算用铀 238 作为燃料
这种燃料超级便宜
而且能持续产热 800 小时
在这个方案里
我们用的是 IC2 冷却剂，把反应堆里的热量导出去
再把它送到热交换器里
接下来照例是烧水来推动涡轮机
这一次
为了避免使用同样昂贵、还会损耗电力的电缆
我们拉了一根长长的传动轴回基地
基地里有一台小发电机，慢慢给大电池组充电
这样以后我们还能继续扩建更大的系统
我们这个新电源要先供给的第一件设备是
半导体制冷器
用来运行新的低温蒸馏塔
从而获取一些惰性气体，做纳米级制造机
从而生产石墨烯部件
这些部件性能惊人，却依然便宜得离谱
值得一提的是，我们现在还能制作碳坩埚
它们足以应付最难处理的材料
我们会用新的电加热器来加热它
它能把温度控制得非常精确
我们刚做出来的是碳化钨
它用于制造更好的压模机，能完成各种工作
不过这些新机器很快就耗尽了我们存的电
很明显，我们需要更大的反应堆
同时也要加快制作速度
于是我们把耗能最高的机器直接连到旧反应堆上，以提高效率
在制作了大量致密板之后
我们终于完成了新的反应堆
这一次我们用了六个反应堆堆芯
填入了不同燃料棒的组合
实现了超过 9000 HU/t 的产量
其中一部分热量用来维持水循环
剩下的则用来加热两台大型殷钢锅炉
它们可以产出 16,000 L/t 蒸汽
这些蒸汽用来带动一台大型涡轮机
输出达到 5,000 RU/t
最后，用大型发电机把它变成 4,000 EU/t
刚好低于 IV 电压
输出之所以不稳定
是因为我们没有在消耗这些能量
而电池箱里的电池已经充满了